Guide to the Edwin Hamlin Woodruff papers, 1888-1938.
Woodruff, Edwin Hamlin papers, 1888-1938
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edwin Hamlin Woodruff papers, 1888-1938.
18-1-1703
Edwin Hamlin Woodruff, 1862-1941.
.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, certificates, and a scrapbook.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, certificates, and a small scrapbook of newspaper clippings and handwritten quotations. Letters are primarily from associates at Stanford University and students from Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University LL.B 1888. Edwin Hamlin was Dean of the Cornell Law School from 1916-1921, and taught there until 1927.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, certificates, and a small scrapbook of newspaper clippings and handwritten quotations. Letters are primarily from associates at Stanford University and students from Cornell University; correspondents include Morris Bishop, George Gleason Bogert, Julian Pleasant Britz, Lord Charnwood, Lewis Clinton, Frederick Diamond Colson, Edmund Ezra Day, John Charles Lounsberry Fish, Felix Frankfurter, James Picken Harrold, George S. Hellman, Mary (Mrs. Timothy) Hopkins, Oscar Lewis, Robert Harper Murray, Jackson E. Reynolds, Sao-Ke Alfred Sze, Martin Travieso, Joseph Edgar Uihlein, and Frederick Campbell Woodward.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Woodruff, Edwin Hamlin, 1862-1941.; Bishop, Morris, 1893-1973.; Bogert, George Gleason, 1884-1977.; Bretz, Julian Pleasant.; Charnwood, Godfrey Rathbone Benson, 1864-1945.; Clinton, Lewis.; Colson, Frederick Diamond.; Day, Edmund Ezra, 1883-1951.; Fish, J. C. L. (John Charles Lounsbury), 1870-1962.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965.; Harrold, James Picken.; Hellman, George Sidney.; Hopkins, Mary.; Lewis, Oscar.; Murray, Robert Harper.; Reynolds, Jackson E.; Sze, Sao-Ke Alfred, 1877-1958.; Travieso, Martin.; Uihlein, Joseph Edgar.; Woodward, Frederick Campbell.; Cornell Law School--Faculty.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Lawyers.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Martin Travieso, San Juan, P.R., Feb. 27, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Julian Pleasant Bretz, Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., Mar. 11, 1936 (Box 1)
  - George Gleason Bogert, University of Chicago Law School, Chicago, Ill., Apr. 23, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Felix Frankfurter, Law School of Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., May 8, 1936 (Box 1)
  - George G. Bogert, Chicago, Ill., June 17, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Sao-Ke Alfred Sze, Chinese Embassy, Washington, D.C., Oct. 8, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Felix Frankfurter, Cambridge, Mass., July 21, 1938 (Box 1)
  - George Sidney Hellman, New York, N.Y., Oct. 8, 1938 (Box 1)
  - James P. Harrold, Chicago, Ill., Nov. 14, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Edmund Ezra Day, Cornell Univ., Ithaca, N.Y., Dec. 7, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Frederic Woodward, University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., Dec. 20, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Felix Frankfurter, Cambridge, Mass., Dec. 27, 1938 (Box 1)
- Other materials
  - Bachelor of Law, Cornell University, June 21, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Degree: Admitted to practice before the Supreme Court, State of New York, Apr. 20, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Certificate: Boy Scouts of America, Harrie (Harry) Woodruff, Apr. 15, 1913 (Box 1)